Register of the Joan Beecher Eichrodt collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- Sound Recordings, 1988-1999 (Boxes 34-40)
  - Chechnia, 1991-1999, undated
    - Groznyĭ refugees in Znamenskoe, 1994 December 19 (Box-folder 35: 25)
      Refugees describe violence in Groznyĭ and how they escaped.
    - Salambek Khadzhiev, 1994 December 21-22 (Box-folder 35: 26)
      The opposition leader discusses the Chechen parliament and his meeting with Dzhokhar Dudaev.
    - Magomed-Khadzhi, 1995 (Box-folder 35: 27)
      Interview with the former Wilhelm Weisserth, an ethnic German deported from Ukraine to Kazakhstan in 1941, on Stalin's deportations and life in Central Asia. He describes meeting his Chechen wife, his conversion to Islam, and interrogations by the NKVD.
    - Salambek Khadzhiev and Lecha Umkhaev on Chechen politics, 1995 (Box-folder 35: 28)
    - Lermontov-Iurt and Akchoĭ-Martan group interviews, 1995 (Box-folder 35: 29)
    - Group interviews on the bus to Vedeno, 1995 (Box-folder 35: 30-31)
      See Box 4, Folder 23 and Box 5, Folder 5 for transcripts.
    - Sleptsovsk refugees, 1995 January (Box-folder 35: 32)
      See Box 5, Folders 1-2 for transcripts.
    - Akhmed Arsanov, 1995 January 5 (Box-folder 35: 33)
      Topics include environmental destruction in the Caucasus, elections in Chechnia and Ingushetia, and Chechen-Ingush relations.
    - Aslambek Aslakhanov, 1995 January 5 (Box-folder 35: 34-35)
      See Box 3, Folder 20 for transcript.
    - Moscow Roundtable on Chechnia, 1995 January 16 (Box-folder 35: 36-38)
      Topics include the Chechen diaspora, Dzhokhar Dudaev, Chechen domestic politics, and relations between Chechnia and the other Caucasian republics. Includes an unrelated panel discussion on private sector development in Russia with Leila Webster, Michael Gould, and Marie Shepherd.
    - Sultan Meduev, 1995 January 18, undated (Box-folder 35: 39-41)
      See Box 4, Folder 13 for transcript.
    - Conference speeches on Chechnia, 1995 January 19-22 (Box-folder 36: 1-2)
      Topics include Chechen-Russian relations, Chechen identity, Stalin's 1944 deportations, and the meaning of democracy in Chechnia.
    - Sleptsovsk group interviews, 1995 January 26 (Box-folder 36: 3-4)
    - Soldiers' mothers, 1995 January 27 (Box-folder 36: 5)
      See Box 5, Folder 3 for transcripts.
    - Ruslan Madiev, 1995 February (Box-folder 36: 6)
      See Box 4, Folder 11 for transcript.
    - Bislan Gantamirov press conference speech, 1995 February (Box-folder 36: 7-8)
    - Tamara Batukaeva and Vakhit Akaev, 1995 April 28 (Box-folder 36: 9)
      Access
      Use copy reference number: 2006c62_a_0004452
      Topics include violence and household searches by Russian soldiers in Chechnia, the war with Russia, and Chechen domestic politics.
    - Vladimir Zorin and refugees from Urus-Martan, 1995 May (Box-folder 36: 10)
      On bombing, violence, and looting in Chechnia.
    - Vladimir Zorin and Lecha Umkhaev at the Daĭmokh Congress, 1995 May (Box-folder 36: 11)
      On Chechen domestic politics and Russian troops in Chechen territory.
    - Speech by Salambek Khadzhiev at the Daimokh Congress, 1995 May (Box-folder 36: 12)
    - Mayor of Shali and officials from Gudermes, 1995 May (Box-folder 36: 13)
      On local government administration in Chechnia.
    - OSCE peace talks with Lecha Magomadov and Usman Imaev, 1995 May (Box-folder 36: 14)
    - Shamil' Beno and Hajj participants, 1995 May 5-6 (Box-folder 36: 15)
      Hajj participants from Tolstoĭ-Iurt discuss violence in the Prigorodnyĭ raĭon and Islam in Chechnia. For transcripts of the Shamil' Beno interview, see Box 3, Folder 24.
    - Mayor of Bachi-Iurt and group interviews at Novogroznenskoe, 1995 May 8 (Box-folder 36: 16-17)
    - Akhmed-Khadzhi Kadyrov, Chechen mufti, 1995 May 9 (Box-folder 36: 18)
      See Box 3, Folder 35 for transcript.
    - Republican Party congress speeches on Chechen domestic affairs, 1995 May 11 (Box-folder 36: 19)
    - Bislan Gantamirov, 1995 May 29 (Box-folder 36: 20)
      See Box 3, Folder 32 for transcript.
    - Vladimir Zorin and Cossack group interview, 1995 June 3 (Box-folder 36: 21)
    - Iusup Soslambekov on Dzhokhar Dudaev and Chechen domestic affairs, 1995 June 25, undated (Box-folder 36: 22-23)
      Tape includes a panel in English on separatist movements in Russia.
    - Aĭna, a Chechen civilian, on violence in Groznyĭ, 1995 July (Box-folder 36: 24)
      Use copy reference number: 2006c62_a_0004463
    - Unidentified Cossack on Cossack-Chechen relations, 1995 July (Box-folder 36: 25)
    - Vakhit Akaev on the Chechen parliament, 1995 August (Box-folder 36: 26)
    - Abuzar Aĭdamirov, 1995 August (Box-folder 36: 27)
      The Chechen writer and poet discusses differences between Islam and the Russian Orthodox Church.
    - Shamil' Beno and Abuzar Aĭdamirov, 1995 August (Box-folder 36: 28)
      Beno discusses the Vaĭnakh party and Islam in Chechnia. Aĭdamirov describes how sharia law would function in Chechnia and Dagestan.
    - Stanitsa Naurskaia Cossacks group interview, 1995 August 9 (Box-folder 36: 29-30)
      Topics include bombings of Groznyĭ, Cossack politics in the Caucasus, organization and political structure of the Cossack community, and Cossack relations with Russia and Chechnia.
    - Cossacks at Chervlënnaia, 1995 August 10 (Box-folder 36: 31)
    - Street interviews with women in Assinovka, 1995 August 11 (Box-folder 36: 32)
      Use copy reference number: 2006c62_a_0004464
      Topics include arrests in Chechnia, the lack of humanitarian aid, unemployment in Chechnia, relations with Ingushetia, and Dzhokhar Dudaev's regime.
    - Iusup Elmurzaev and others in Akchoĭ-Martan and Urus-Martan, 1995 August 11 (Box-folder 36: 33-34)
      Topics include village administration in Chechnia, domestic political conflicts, and the war with Russia.
    - Chechen women group interview, 1995 October (Box-folder 36: 35)
      Use copy reference number: 2006c62_a_0004457
    - Librarian from Groznyĭ on the destruction of Chechen libraries, archives and museums during the war, 1996 (Box-folder 36: 36)
    - Speech in Chechen by Zelimkhan Iandarbiev, 1996 (Box-folder 36: 37)
    - Mustafa Gakaev on Chechen domestic politics and Russian-Chechen relations, 1996 (Box-folder 36: 38-41)
      Includes an interview with the head of a Chechen cultural center in Novgorod recorded at a Chechen diaspora conference.
    - Daĭmokh party meeting, 1996 (Box-folder 36: 42)
      In Russian and Chechen.
    - Akhmed Arsanov on Dzhokhar Dudaev and elections in Chechnia, 1996 (Box-folder 37: 1)
    - Unidentified Chechen on Stalin's deportations, 1996 (Box-folder 37: 2-3)
      Includes Heritage Foundation discussion panels on privatization in Russia and Nagorno-Karabakh negotiations.
    - Voice of America Correspondent's Report: "Russian-Chechen Negotiations,", 1996 (Box-folder 37: 4)
      On a cease-fire agreement between Russia and Chechnia.
    - Chechen diaspora conference in Tver', 1996 May (Box-folder 37: 5-6)
    - Nikolaĭ Koshman, Moscow's envoy to Chechnia, on Chechen domestic politics, 1996 May 22 (Box-folder 37: 7)
      Includes a Voice of America Background Report, "Chechen Diaspora: Elections."
    - Vladimir Zorin on the "Geroĭ dnia" television program, 1996 May 23 (Box-folder 37: 8)
      Interview with Zorin, a member of the Russian delegation to Chechnia.
    - Ruslan Khasbulatov, 1996 May 23, undated (Box-folder 37: 9-11)
      Topics include the 1996 elections, Chechen-Russian relations, corruption in the Caucasus, and Dzhokhar Dudaev.
    - Iusup Soslambekov, 1996 May 26 (Box-folder 37: 12)
      Topics include Stalin's 1944 deportations of Chechens and Ingush, characteristics of the Chechen people, and the conflict between Chechnia and Russia.
    - Said-Khasan Abumuslimov press conference on negotiations between Russia and Chechnia, 1996 June (Box-folder 37: 13)
    - Salambek Maigov on negotiations between Russia and Chechnia, 1996 June 2 (Box-folder 37: 14)
    - Ruslan Kataev and Imran Dakhshukaev on negotiations between Russia and Chechnia, 1996 June 4 (Box-folder 37: 15)
    - Said-Khasan Abumuslimov press conference, 1996 June 5 (Box-folder 37: 16)
      Includes interview with Azamat Nal'giev, a member of the Iabloko party in Ingushetia, on Russian elections.
    - Two Chechen women, Zeĭnap and Maia, describe the war in Chechnia, 1996 June 25 (Box-folder 37: 17)
      Use copy reference number: 2006c62_a_0004470
    - Voice of America Backround Report: "The Cossacks Vote," Krasnodar, 1996 July 3 (Box-folder 37: 18)
      Includes interviews with Cossacks in Krasnodar on Russian politics.
    - Dalgat Akhmedkhanov on the war in Chechnia, 1996 July 8 (Box-folder 37: 19)
    - Tim Guldeman, U.S. Congressional hearing on human rights violations in Chechnia, 1997 (Box-folder 37: 20)
    - Tim Guldeman, speech before the Helsinki Committee on Chechen-Russian relations, 1997 (Box-folder 37: 21)
    - Election observers in Chechnia, 1997 January (Box-folder 37: 22)
    - OSCE press conference on elections in Chechnia, 1997 January (Box-folder 37: 23)
      Includes an interview with a nurse who had taken in 30 Dagestani orphans.
    - Movladi Udugov on Islamic rule in Chechnia, 1997 January 14 (Box-folder 37: 24)
    - Abdulla Vatsuev and Vakhit Akaev on Islam and Wahhabi missionaries in the Caucasus, 1997 January 18-19 (Box-folder 37: 25)
    - Lecha Umkhaev on parliamentary elections in Chechnia, 1997 January 19 (Box-folder 37: 26)
    - Mustafa [?] on parliamentary elections in Chechnia, 1997 January 25 (Box-folder 37: 27)
    - Voice of America Correspondent's Report: "The Candidates,", 1997 January 26 (Box-folder 37: 28)
      Eichrodt's report on parliamentary elections in Chechnia.
    - Television report with Tim Guldeman, 1997 January 30 (Box-folder 37: 29)
      The OSCE representative discusses elections in Chechnia. Includes an interview with a Chechen parliamentarian.
    - Voice of America Correspondent's Report: "Tim Guldeman and Joan Beecher on Chechen Domestic Politics,", 1997 February (Box-folder 37: 30)
    - Inauguration of Aslan Maskhadov, 1997 February (Box-folder 37: 31)
      Mainly in Chechen.
    - Said-Hassan Sarnaev on the destruction of cultural property in Groznyĭ, 1997 February 1 (Box-folder 37: 32)
      Recorded during a drive around the Chechen capital. Interrupted by an interview with Mumadi Saidaev, Chair of the Chechen Electoral Commission.
    - Voice of America Correspondent's Report: "Chechnia: Final Election Results,", 1997 February 2 (Box-folder 37: 33)
      Includes an interview with Vakhit Akaev on destruction of cultural property in Chechnia during the war.
    - Zelimkhan Iandarbiev speech in Chechen, 1997 February 4 (Box-folder 37: 34)
      Recorded from television.
    - Vakha Zakiev, Ministry of Internal Affairs, 1997 February 5 (Box-folder 37: 35)
      On politics, crime, and the police force in Chechnia. Includes an interview with a Russian living in Chechnia on why he chooses to stay in the region.
    - Maĭerbek Vachagaev and Aslan Maskhadov press conference, 1997 February 5-6 (Box-folder 37: 36)
      Includes a Voice of America report on the destruction of cultural property in Groznyĭ during the war with Russia.
    - Aslan Alievich Maskhadov press conference speech, 1997 February 13 (Box-folder 37: 37)
      On the war in Chechnia and negotiations with Russia.
    - Street interviews on Chechen politics with voters, 1997 June 22 (Box-folder 37: 38)
      Includes speech in Chechen.
    - Aslan Maskhadov, 1997 November 13 (Box-folder 37: 39)
      On Chechen domestic politics, his career, and relations with Russia.
    - Aslambek Aslakhanov on Chechen politics, 1999 (Box-folder 37: 40)
    - Shatoĭ refugees, undated (Box-folder 37: 41)
      On Russian soldiers and violence in Chechnia.
    - Arsamik, undated (Box-folder 37: 42)
      In Chechen.
    - Speech in Chechen, 1990s (Box-folder 38: 1)
  - Dagestan, 1990-1993, 1996-1997
    - B.A. Kel'dasov, 1990 November (Box-folder 38: 2)
      Topics include Nogais in the Caucasus, independence movements in Dagestan and Checheno-Ingushetia, and Cossacks in the Caucasus.
    - Tenglik movement, 1991 (Box-folder 38: 3)
      An unidentified leader of Tenglik, a Kumyk movement in Dagestan, discusses politics and national autonomy in Dagestan.
    - Lezgians, 1992 (Box-folder 38: 4)
      See Box 5, Folder 21 for transcript.
    - Vasif Meĭlanov and Eduard Urazaev, 1992 (Box-folder 38: 5)
      See Box 5, Folder 22 for transcript.
    - Vazif Meĭlanov on politics in Dagestan, 1992 January (Box-folder 38: 6)
    - Mustafaev and Dzhabrailov (Kumyks in Dagestan), 1992 January (Box-folder 38: 7)
      On Islam in Dagestan and democracy in the Caucasus.
    - Voice of America Background Report: "Northern Caucasus,", 1992 January 20 (Box-folder 38: 8)
      Report from Makhachkala on separatist movements in Dagestan. Includes interview with Eduard Urazaev on the role of Dagestan in the Caucasus.
    - Dadash [?] on Cossacks, politics and ethnic relations in Dagestan, 1992 January 20 (Box-folder 38: 9-10)
    - Kumyks in Dagestan, group interview, 1992 January 22 (Box-folder 38: 11)
      On relations between Russians, Kumyks, and Avars in Dagestan.
    - Background Report: "National Problems in Dagestan,", 1992 January 22 (Box-folder 38: 12)
      On relations between Nogais, Kumyks, Avars, Cossacks, and Lezgians in Dagestan. Report followed by interview with Novoe delo staff in Dagestan.
    - Dagestan historian, 1992 February 3 (Box-folder 38: 13)
      Topics include Dagestan before the Soviet era and collections at the Institute of National Culture related to the history of the North Caucasus.
    - Dagestan Minister of Trade, 1992 September 21 (Box-folder 38: 14)
    - Melidov, 1993 August 6 (Box-folder 38: 15)
      On Islam in Dagestan and the North Caucasus.
    - Makhachev, an Avar, and Khachilaev, a Lak, on national movements in Dagestan, 1993 August 9 (Box-folder 38: 16)
    - Khasaviurt group interview on the Russian presidential elections, 1996 June (Box-folder 38: 17)
    - Eduard Urazaev on elections in Dagestan, 1996 July 12 (Box-folder 38: 18-19)
      Side B includes witness accounts of violence in Chechnia in 1995.
    - Vazif Meĭlanov on politics in Dagestan, 1997 November 18 (Box-folder 38: 20)
  - Georgia, 1991-1992, 1994
    - Kennan Institute panel on Georgian independence, 1991 February 27 (Box-folder 38: 21)
      In Georgian with simultaneous English translation.
    - Jumber Patiašvili and Merab Uridia, 1992 September 6 (Box-folder 38: 22)
    - Panel on Georgia at the National Press Club in Washington, DC, 1993 September 4 (Box-folder 38: 23)
    - Member of the Georgian women's peace delegation, 1994 June 8 (Box-folder 38: 24)
      A delegate to the United States discusses the conflict between Georgia and Abkhazia and her hopes for peace. Side B is a television news report on the Russian parliament.
  - Ingushetia, 1992-1996
    - Press conference on independence of Ingushetia, 1992 (Box-folder 38: 25)
      Topics include relations with Chechnia and the establishment of borders.
    - Beksultan Seĭnaroev, 1992 February (Box-folder 38: 26)
      Ingush lawyer on border disputes and relations between Chechnia and Ingushetia.
    - Ingush doctor, 1992 May 8 (Box-folder 38: 27)
      A doctor from the Prigorodnyĭ raĭon on her experiences during the Ingush-Ossetian conflict.
    - Ingush women group interview, 1992 November 16 (Box-folder 38: 28)
      On occupation of Ingushetia and the conflict with North Ossetia over the Prigorodnyĭ raĭon.
    - Issa Kostoev, 1992 October 27, 1993 February 9 (Box-folder 38: 29-30)
      See Box 6, Folder 2 for transcripts.
    - Ingush group discussion of Prigorodnyĭ raĭon and the conflict with Ossetia, circa 1993 (Box-folder 38: 31)
    - Ingush refugees, 1993 (Box-folder 38: 32-33)
      See Box 6, Folders 5-6 for transcripts.
    - Ingush Congresses, 1993 January and July (Box-folder 38: 34-40)
      Zelimkhan Iandarbiev, Ruslan Khasbulatov, and others discuss the conflict between Ingushetia and North Ossetia, the refugee problem, and elections.
    - Russian wife of Ingush man, Prigorodnyĭ raĭon, 1993 February (Box-folder 38: 41)
      A Russian woman describes her life in Prigorodnyĭ raĭon, conflicts between Ingush and Ossetians, and differences between men and women.
    - Ruslan Aushev, president of Ingushetia, 1993 May 19 (Box-folder 38: 42)
      Topics include relations with Chechnia and establishing borders.
    - Boris Agapov, Mark Pliev and Issa Kostoev, 1993 May 19 (Box-folder 39: 1)
    - Timurlan Mutaliev on the history of Ingushetia, 1993 May 20 (Box-folder 39: 2)
    - Ruslan Aushev and Aleksandr Iakovlev press conference, 1993 August 2 (Box-folder 39: 3)
      On the conflict between North Ossetia and Ingushetia.
    - Ruslan Aushev, 1995 January 24 (Box-folder 39: 4)
      See Box 5, Folder 25 for transcript.
    - Boris Agapov, vice-president of Ingushetia, 1995 February 3 (Box-folder 39: 5)
      Topics include the refugee problem, the conflict with Ossetia, and the division of administrative duties with the president.
    - Ruslan Aushev speech on conflicts in the Caucasus, 1996 May 3 (Box-folder 39: 6)
    - Correspondent's Report: "Chechen Vote Reaction," filed from Nazran', 1996 June (Box-folder 39: 7)
    - Election poll in Ingushetia, speech by Ruslan Aushev, and Movladi Udugov press conference, 1996 June 6-7 (Box-folder 39: 8)
    - Street interviews in Ingushetia on the Russian presidential elections, 1996 June 7-8 (Box-folder 39: 9-10)
    - Nazran' negotiations, 1996 June 9 (Box-folder 39: 11)
      Street interviews concerning ceasefire negotiations between Chechnia and Russia.
    - Press conference on elections in Ingushetia, 1996 June 12 (Box-folder 39: 12)
    - Voice of America Background Report: "Russian Elections in Ingushetia,", 1996 June 13 (Box-folder 39: 13)
      Includes street interviews in Kabardino-Balkaria on the Russian elections.
  - Kabardino-Balkariia, 1993, 1996, undated
    - Speeches at Nal'chik rally, 1993 July 17 (Box-folder 39: 14)
      On politics in the Caucasus and relations with Russia.
    - Voice of America Background Report: "North Caucasus Elections," Nal'chik, 1996 June 14 (Box-folder 39: 15)
      Includes interview with the editor of Gazeta Iuga on the Russian elections and voters in Kabardino-Balkariia.
    - Street interviews on the Russian elections, 1996 June 13 (Box-folder 39: 16)
    - Polling station group interviews on the Russian elections, 1996 June 16 (Box-folder 39: 17)
    - Group interview in upper Balkariia; discussion of Balkar language and history, undated (Box-folder 39: 18)
  - Krasnodarskiĭ kraĭ, 1996-1997
    - Timashevsk group interviews on the Russian elections, 1996 June 29 (Box-folder 39: 19-20)
    - Kuznetsov on the Russian presidential elections in Krasnodar, 1996 February (Box-folder 39: 21)
    - Aleksandr Mikhaĭlovich Zhdanovskiĭ, 1996 July 1 (Box-folder 39: 22-23)
      Topics include political activities of the Kuban Cossacks and Russian elections in Krasnodar.
    - Voice of America Background Report, "Russia Votes: The South,", 1996 July 5 (Box-folder 39: 24)
      Includes interview with Dykhanov on elections in Russia.
    - Bektimirov, 1997 February (Box-folder 39: 25)
      A Tatar from Krasnodar discusses his Chechen neighbors.
  - North Ossetia, circa 1992-1993
    - Tselaev on politics in North Ossetia, circa 1992 (Box-folder 39: 26)
    - Unidentified Ossetian song, circa 1992 (Box-folder 39: 27)
    - North Ossetia trip, circa 1992 (Box-folder 39: 28)
      A discussion of Ossetian ruins and cultural landmarks recorded while driving outside Vladikavkaz.
    - Astemir Tsomaev and the Demokraticheskaia Ossetiia movement, 1992 February 3 (Box-folder 39: 29-30)
    - Ossetian refugees, 1993 February 2 (Box-folder 39: 31-32)
      See Box 6, Folder 25 for transcript.
  - Russia, 1987-1988, 1990-1993, 1996
    - Congress of the Peoples of the East (S"ezd narodov Vostoka), 1987 March 17, 1990 September 28, undated (Box-folder 39: 33-39)
      Recordings of conference proceedings. See Box 7, Folders 15-25 for transcripts and related documents.
    - Brookings Institution panel on the Soviet Union, 1988 February 17 (Box-folder 39: 40)
    - People's Deputies Altaĭ Nikolaevich Piche-ool from Tuva and Nikolaĭ Medvedev from Mordoviia, 1990 (Box-folder 40: 1)
      On sovereignty of the republics and Gorbachev's federation plan.
    - Shelov-Sheverdiaev on Gorbachev's federation plan, 1990 (Box-folder 40: 2)
    - Mirkhan Khamzin and other Tatar activists, 1990 September 28 (Box-folder 40: 3)
      On pan-Turkic movements in the Soviet Union.
    - Eremeĭ Danilovich Aĭpin on national autonomy movements in the RSFSR, 1990 October 22 (Box-folder 40: 4)
    - Nikolai Osipov, 1990 October 25 (Box-folder 40: 5)
      See Box 7, Folder 8 for transcript.
    - Deputy from Chitinskaia oblast', 1990 November (Box-folder 40: 6)
      On economic development in his region and different paths to a Russian federation.
    - Conference, Natsional'naia ustroĭstvo i natsional'nye otnosheniia, 1990 November 1 (Box-folder 40: 7)
    - Krupnik on autonomy movements in the RSFSR, 1990 November 13 (Box-folder 40: 8)
    - Alekseĭ Salmin, 1990 November 20-21 (Box-folder 40: 9-10)
      Topics include ethnic relations, autonomy movements in the republics, the Russian constitution, and options for a federal treaty in Russia.
    - Kaadyr-ool Alekseevich Bicheldeĭ, 1990 December 3 (Box-folder 40: 11)
      A deputy from Tuva on sovereignty of the republics and Gorbachev's federation plan.
    - Nikolaĭ Medvedev, 1990 December 4 (Box-folder 40: 12)
      On sovereignty and national autonomy movements in the RSFSR.
    - Interview with two deputies from Khanty-Mansiĭskiĭ avtonomnyĭ okrug on local government, 1990 December 7 (Box-folder 40: 13)
      Includes a speech by Ramazan Abdulatipov.
    - Russian Congress Union Treaty, 1990 December 8 (Box-folder 40: 14)
      Debates and speeches related to Gorbachev's federation plan.
    - Kaadyr-ool Alekseevich Bicheldeĭ, 1991 June (Box-folder 40: 15)
      On relations between Russia and sovereign republics.
    - Alekseĭ Salmin, 1991 June 14 (Box-folder 40: 16)
      On autonomy movements and national sovereignty in the RSFSR.
    - Summit speeches on economic development in Russia, 1992 (Box-folder 40: 17)
    - Speech by unidentified man on the Russian parliament, 1992 July 22 (Box-folder 40: 18)
      Relates primarily to economic development in Russia.
    - Ol'ga Vasil'eva, 1993 May 8 (Box-folder 40: 19)
      On a conference of Cossacks from southern Russia.
    - Viacheslav Igrunov, 1993 September 9 (Box-folder 40: 20)
      On economics in Russia, balance of power, and sovereignty of the republics.
    - Televised debate on ratification of the Russian constitution, 1993 December 9-10 (Box-folder 40: 21-22)
      Features representatives from various political parties.
    - Viacheslav Igrunov on Russian elections, 1996 May 22 (Box-folder 40: 23)
    - Viacheslav Mikhaĭlov on Russian elections and negotiations with Chechnia, 1996 May 29 (Box-folder 40: 24)
    - Sergeĭ [?] on elections in Russia, 1996 June 13 (Box-folder 40: 25)
    - Grigoriĭ Iavlinskiĭ, "Geroĭ dnia," NTV, 1996 June 21 (Box-folder 40: 26)
      The Iabloko politician discusses Russian elections.
    - Sergeĭ Nikiforov and Boris Gromov, 1996 July 2 (Box-folder 40: 27)
      Members of the political group "Chest' i rodina" discuss politics in the Russian Federation.
  - South Ossetia, 1993
    - Oleg Teziev, 1993 (Box-folder 40: 28)
      Prime minister of South Ossetia discusses relations with Georgia and North Ossetia.
  - Miscellaneous, 1991-1994, 1996-1997